We're reading through this research and
we're like, "Oh [__] I can definitely
hack something I'm hacking on right now
with this." So,
>> best part of hacking when you can just,
you know, critical thing, right?
>> Yeah, dude.
Not sure y'all know this, but two of the
most respected hackers in the CTPB
community, Bus Factor and XSS Doctor,
are now running monthly hackalongs on
the CTB Discord. Okay, you got to check
this out. CT ctb.-ow/isord.
We find bugs almost every time we hack.
It's crazy. And and oftentimes it's not
even the people running the hackalongs.
It's the the community members that are
hacking along with us. it. You
definitely increase your chance of
finding a bug by being on these
hackalons. So, check them out.
ctv.showisord.
Join Bus XSS Doctor and yours truly. And
uh let's pop some bugs. All right, let's
go back to the show.
All right, man. Well, we just had a
false start where I didn't press the
record button.
>> Yeah, I made so many good jokes.
>> Oh my gosh. But we're we're we're back.
Um guys, this is the Portswiger top 10
web hacking techniques of 2025 episode.
And guys, I know I know I complain about
it every year, but this episode is a
monster to prep for because these are
very technical pieces of research. And
now we are going to try to articulate
them to you in the audio medium, which
is still challenging after three years.
>> Yeah. Hacking is kind of like text first
in the same way that coding is, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> it's it's it's going to be a beast, but
we're going to give it a shot. Um, there
was a lot of other awesome research also
in the nominations, which I think um we
definitely should go back and review. I
think uh 100, no, 63 pieces of research
contended this year, which is
significantly fewer than 121 that was
submitted last year.
>> Yeah. You you and you and Brandon do an
episode on that. So,
>> yeah. Yeah, dude. Okay, I see you trying
to weasle your way out of that research.
Um, all right. Well, let's let's get to
it, man. Uh, we've got it kind of
divvied up by capability rather than by
like, uh, order. Um, so what's going to
happen is Joseph is going to take 10 and
nine. I'm going to take eight and seven
and we're going to kind of go back and
forth. So, we're going to jump around a
little bit, but first one up is parser
differentials when interpretation
becomes a vulnerability. And you're
gonna take that one, right?
>> That's right. Yeah. So, this got 10th
place. Um, it's a video, not it's not
like um like an official white paper or
anything like that. Um,
>> yeah, it's a it's just a YouTube video.
It was a talk at offensive con 25 by
George. Um, but he is a GitLab engineer
and it's a pretty it's a pretty great
talk. I think I really love partial
issues and so it's the reason I grabbed
this one because I got into the doc
before Justin did and was able to snag
this one. Um, so what I mean you should
just go watch the talk anyone. I mean
it's not that long. It's 28 minutes and
I'm sure if you're watching it on 2x,
you know it's even faster. But what
what's really neat was that he looked at
a bunch of different parser
differentials. And he was mostly
thinking about them in the differences
of like you know if there's a tech stack
that has like go running at one point
and then python later how does it handle
specifically um YAML or actually sorry
no YAML was one of the later ones. Um
yeah no yeah almost like the the bulk of
what he found in the end but um he was
looking at different things between like
Kubernetes and Java and other things. Um
but I just wanted to bring to the
audience like basically the the lowest
hanging fruit here like the stuff that's
like most valuable to try and basically
the first one was just parameter
injection. So there was two RO
parameters. One was like setting it to
admin. One was just setting it as like
roll like a empty list and because the
the parsers handled it separately. Um it
basically bypassed the JavaScript check
which was which was checking the second
one and then whenever it actually got to
the Java implementation it the it read
the like the backend uh server side code
read the first one set them to an admin.
And I think I can actually share my
screen on that exact screenshot. Yeah,
let me share it real quick for the
people who are watching on YouTube. Um
this one right here. So this is in a
parser differential in HTTP rather than
in in YAML or something like that.
>> No, it's JavaScript and Erlang. Um I
don't know where it was actually like
what repos
JSON here.
>> Yeah, that's what I'm saying. Yeah, it's
it's like a JSON input. Um and Erlang
like whenever it's parsing this, it
accepts the first role, but whenever
JavaScript is parsing this, it accepts
the the latter role here. So for the for
the listeners, basically it's what I
said just a minute ago. It's just the
the key is rolls and there's there's two
of those keys and the first one is a
list that includes admin and the second
one is not and so you're able to get a
you know JavaScript saw an empty array
whereas Erlang sent saw the underscore
admin role and granted that to the user.
So um you know kind of neat pretty cool
we've seen stuff like this before. Um
the second one the second example he
thought he showed which I thought was
pretty neat was a double off tag a
double authorization header. I bet this
exists in way more places. So the first
one was a nonssigned fake admin JWT and
then the second O header was a legit
bearer uh token that the application
gave you and you could and you could put
>> Exactly. It's really cool. You could put
basically uh attributes that you want
into that first nonsigned one. You know,
I think all of us have tried this, but
I've only ever done it with one. Right.
You take you change the legit one to
nunsign. You don't do both.
>> Wow. Okay. Okay, so he's smuggling in a
second authorization bearer and the the
the middleware, you know, the the front
piece is checking for that second
bearer, which is a legit JWT signed low
priv, but the back end is actually
grabbing the O bearer that is algorithm
none with all of our stuff in it and
that's not checking the signature and
it's just accepting all of our crazy
attributes.
>> Yep, that's exactly right.
>> Dang, dude.
>> It's really cool. Yeah. And this then
the rest of this talk is really neat.
It's all about YAML and there's a bunch
of cool things that YAML had that I
didn't know. So, one is this like binary
thing. You can just like prefix a line
with like exclamation mark exclamation
mark binary and then that key or it's
like sometimes it's keys, sometimes it's
values get like are allowed to be
interpreted as B64 encoded um content.
It's really weird. So, uh, for the
listeners, I'm sharing on screen, um, a
couple different things, but, uh, he,
uh, yeah, that that one is go back to
that really quickly. Okay,
>> so here here, let me read this to you.
The the bang the bang bang binary tag
can be used to base 64 encode arbitrary
binary data inside of YAML. So, I think
this is most useful for like sending in
like audio or images or things like
that.
>> Wow. Yeah, that makes sense. So,
essentially, and you can use that in a
key or in a value, right? So it's like
an operation that is being run on top of
a you know the value that is being
provided in in YAML here. So in the
example right there that you've got up
on the screen it's saying lang is
Python. Okay. Okay. Okay. It's saying
lang lang is python but then it's doing
bang bang binary and then providing the
b 64 encoded version of
>> of lang of l overwriting it. Yes.
>> Oh my god. and and and then bang binary
and then it again and so the output of
this as you as you watch here uh or as
like the listeners
is like I don't know why this says first
and second instead of he should have
kept this going with the same heacular
>> but I see what you're saying
>> but anyways yeah so so basically you can
you can trick things and then later on
he does this other thing with it's um
merge
>> or actually so actually I'm I get this a
little conflated because listeners
honestly I took this and I told Claude
code extend this research and look for
more stuff like this. There's another
thing called merge and I can't remember
if he used merge or if my cloud code
thought of the idea of using merge, but
there there is a YAML there's a YAML
thing called merge. Yeah, I think it's
totally my cloud code and not in this
talk. Basically, there is a um another
YAML um declarative or whatever it's
called function that's like greater or
it's less than less than and it merges
the next key that you have into the
first key. And this is also very
problematic for parser differences. Um,
so anyways, pretty cool talk. I think
people would get a lot out of it. Um,
and you should definitely go watch it,
>> dude. Yeah. What the heck are these
shorthand tags in YAML?
>> Do you just want me to Are you Do you
want to share? Do you want me to
>> No, no, no, no, no. You You go ahead.
I'm just like, you got me nerd sniped a
little bit right now. How Wow. There's
like all sorts of transformations you
can do
>> on YAML, man. There's just going to be
an absolute insane number of problems
because of this.
>> Yeah, this is the this is the table I
showed you.
>> There's lots of crazy stuff too where
like uh if you put like yes or no or
true or false and like in some it's
interpreted as a string and therefore
results out as true even though you
wrote the word false but it's a string
and strings equate to true. Like dude,
there's so many YAML parser issues. And
what's what I'm really hopeful on this
with with my own research and finding is
that um in places like GitHub CI/CD,
this will be like mega critical uh as
far as actual impact.
>> Wow, dude. Yeah, that's sick. So
definitely something to look into there.
I'm very surprised to see that being
used in keys as well, right? because the
the YAML file that you showed, you know,
it defined an attribute lang equals
whatever or lang um colon whatever, but
then it provided a binary version of
lang, right? And then provided an
alternative value and then depending on
how those are prioritized with the
binary decoding. One may do the the you
know tag resolution before parsing the
line above it or it might be after.
>> So so much opportunity for parser
differentials there. Yes,
>> that's sick.
>> Very sick.
>> Wow. And and I just and you know, of
course, I love
>> AI stuff. All the AI stuff is marked
down to HTML. Same exact thing, right? A
bunch across a bunch of different
libraries. And so I want to actually
apply the same research logic that he
did and that I had cloud code dupe like
as like a followup to that research to
the markdown to um HTML parser. So I'll
let you know if that finds anything.
>> Yeah, dude. It was so funny cuz I did
the exact same thing that you did with
this, which is like we're reading
through this research and we're like,
"Oh [__]
>> I can definitely hack something I'm
hacking on right now with this." So, you
like, you know, kicked off a cloud code
and and I'll I'll explain the one that I
just did later, but um I I kicked off a
a cloud code instance as well and it
found a V while I was reading this
research,
>> which is nuts. Um so, crazy world we're
living in here. It really is. Um
>> all right, number nine is playing with
HP2 Connect. I'm going to let you take
that, but first I'm going to jump down
to XSS leak leaking cross origin
redirects. And this was kind of a of an
interesting one because uh it's called
XSS leaks, but it doesn't have anything
to do with XSS. It's a cross-sight
subdomain leak, which is a variety of XS
leak. Okay. Um and essentially what this
research is about is leaking cross
origin uh redirects, which is a very
specific situation. Uh it's kind of CTFy
to be honest, but um
>> the website the website is a little CTFy
too.
>> Yeah, it looks great.
>> If you look at the
>> if any for all the listeners, it's like
a beautiful like um yeah, purple and
black website that's like very typical
like hackery.
>> Yeah. Terminal vibes. Uh yeah. Um but
and there are some some applications for
this research for sure. Like I I've run
into a situation where I need to know a
subdomain like this uh in cloud
environments where it'll generate like
an arbitrary subdomain or whatever and
if you can leak that subdomains that
subdomain itself then that will be
helpful for like exploiting an XSS or
something. Um but essentially what this
write up is focused on is how do we
abuse the Chrome connection pool to uh
leak those uh cross origin hosts. And um
the TLDDR behind this is that Chrome has
a connection pool cap at 256 concurrent
requests and six requests for uh a given
origin. Okay. So what the um the
attacker here does is he fills all of
the way up the uh Chrome connection pool
and then abuses the order that free
spots are filled within Chrome. Okay. So
you might think it's like first in first
out. It's not. that would make too much
sense. The way that Chrome actually does
this is it will sort by port scheme and
then host right. So if you have let's
say you have 255 you know concurrent
requests in the connection pool and a
slot opens up right and there's two
requests pending
>> uh Chrome will first look at the
priority of those requests right which
we can override to high using like fetch
um and then it will you know if the
priority is high for both of them then
it will then sort by port than scheme
then host right so the lower port is
better so if you got a request to port
80 that's going to be prioritized over
something that's, you know, port one
1337 or something like that. Um, but the
real magic comes in when you make the
port and the scheme the same. So, all
you're doing is actually uh having
Chrome compare the host uh
lexographically. And I had to look up
that word, Joseph, lexographically, but
essentially just
>> Yeah. Well, I was also mispronouncing
it. So, I had to look it up how to say
it, you know, before this episode. Um,
but essentially it's just like in
alphabetical order, right? Um, so if you
have a host that, you know, uh, starts
with an A or whatever, that's going to
be prioritized over a host that starts
with a B, right? And because of that,
you can do a binary search, uh, and
figure out whether the request on on the
cross origin page was issued or was let
into the connection pool first or
whether your request was. So here's how
you do that. Okay, so first you fill up
the connection pool. Then you use in
this scenario it was a hash change event
to trigger a cross origin request. Okay,
so now that request is requesting to get
access to the Chrome connection pool,
but then it cannot. Right? Uh and then
we also at the same time trigger our
guess for what that subdomain might be.
Right? So now there's two requests
competing for that for an open slot in
the connection pool. Mhm.
>> Then you release one of the uh slots in
the connection pool and you trigger how
long it takes for your request to go
through. Okay.
>> Um and if it's a longer piece, you know,
if it takes longer, then you know that
it actually let first the cross origin
request through and then your request
through, right? And it and if it's
shorter response time, then it knows
that you know your request got priority
over the cross origin request, right?
which means your um request was
lexographically smaller than the one
that uh you wanted to trigger on the
cross origin request. Right? So this
gives you a binary yes or no on whether
your guess is lexographically greater or
less than the target origin and you can
then just perform a binary search on
that to very very quickly extract the
full subdomain of that uh target page.
Um, so not going to lie, it's pretty
pretty big brain, dude. And I had to
read it like three times to understand
it. Um, I think there's very few
situations where this will be helpful.
But one of the things they did, um, you
know, mention as well, is that you can
use this to determine things about the
user, sort of like a cross-sight leak on
whether the user is an admin or not.
Mhm.
>> Um, and that just requires, you know,
you being able to do one or two of these
things by
>> because you already know the host.
>> Exactly. So, so you can just hit, you
know, slashloin or whatever. And then
that makes the user redirect to either
admin.lochost.com
or, you know, regular user.lochost.com.
And by, you know, creating a um request
that splits the difference between those
two, you can determine where the user
landed um which will give you
information about the user. So there's
there's lots of sort of hackery ways
that you can abuse this, but
understanding the nuances of the Chrome
connection pool um is yet another
cross-sight leak vector that we have um
in our pocket. So I don't know if it'll
be useful to anyone, but that it
definitely was for this CTF. Is it
possible that I'm just wondering like if
there are ever
um So this can't this doesn't do
anything with parameters though, right?
>> No, no, just the host
>> thing. Well, if there's ever a secret
stored as a subdomain,
then then you could binary search it
out. What I was thinking was like if it
worked in parameters, if there's ever
like an endpoint that takes a secret as
a parameter and then like does something
different if it's valid versus if it's
not, then you could binary search it to
excfiltrate out the parameter. Yeah.
Yeah. There there are some weird
situations with some of Google's um like
user generated content stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> That where the actual hash of the
content gets placed as a subdomain and
they use that as an isolation factor. So
there there could be some applications
there. There could be some applications
in cloud where you need to know you know
the the sub resource that is being
loaded there. Um so yeah it was it was a
cool it was a cool one for sure. I
definitely see why it made the the um
the top 10. So, shout out to Salvator
and uh shout out to uh CTVB's own Jorian
as well uh who was able to solve that uh
in the CTF it looks like.
>> Hey, question. What happens if the host
also matches?
>> I don't know, man.
>> Yeah, it's probably just some it's just
chrome logic, right? Maybe it becomes
random or something, but I that I was
just curious if they touch on that.
>> That is interesting. I think it would
actually I think it's a hash actually.
So I think it would just overwrite. But
that that doesn't make any sense. It
would just conflict. I don't know. Maybe
that would trigger an error or
something. That that's an interesting
edge case.
>> Yep.
>> All right. You want to jump back up to
nine?
>> Yes. Yep. So um until we just did a
whole another breakdown of this uh
personally me and Justin off camera we
where we realize the actual impact of
this.
>> You can't call us out like that, man.
Come on.
>> Yeah, I can. It's fine. The audience
needs to know the back room. The back
what's it called? the back office talk
that happens here. Yeah. So, basically
this was a this is um a blog by Flom f
Loom MB um on their blog which is
blog.flom.net.
But um the connect verb first of all I
just love like underlying stuff right
like HTTP verbs and stuff like that for
some reason like they're just so OG and
cool. But anyways and you just you don't
get to use them that often like when
trace works it's uh it's uh always like
neat. And so anyways, this is the
connect verb. And in HTTP1, the connect
verb was just like kind of like just a
raw connection. Everything from the
client went to the server. Everything
from the server went to the client. But
what he talks about in this is how HTTP
connect HTTP2
connect.
>> Sorry that I speak so fast listeners. um
it um is completely different and so it
uses this binary protocol where the
fundamental unit is called a frame just
like usual and the frame carries like a
stream identifier and there's like um
yeah a bunch of different fields.
>> This is this is the structure of HTTP2.
Yeah,
>> that's right. And it it even like does
like a like a settings setup at the
beginning. Uh but the TLDDR is that it's
complex and it's like so there's you
know lots of room for new things to
happen basically new vulnerabilities or
just new issues to happen.
>> I think the uh the the key line is here.
I'm going to read from it. It says
streams allow multipplexing which means
a single HP2 connection can host
multiple simultaneous connect tunnels.
Right.
>> Yep. And what's really interesting is it
allows you to connect to arbitrary IP
and ports through that tunnel. So what
this person did which was they they
built a scanner in Go and what um even
though there wasn't like good support
for HTTP2 yet there is a package and
they basically Swiss army knifed what is
effectively a port scanner and fullblown
SSRF through the connectverb. Um yeah I
I don't understand how this is not just
like a straight up vulnerability. I I
guess if you're supporting HTTP2, you
should just block the connect verb. Um
because I don't even know where you
would add the logic to protect against
this. But um they show here that
whenever it's a successful connection,
it shows a status 200. If it fails, it
shows a headers frame with a status 503.
And so after this, after you listen to
this podcast, you should go check if any
of your bug bounty targets support the
connect verb on HTTP2 because if they
do, you can basically scan via SSRF for
any internal hosts.
>> Yeah, it was kind of weird, you know,
because we read through this thing and
we're like control Fing for SSRF. Like
we can't find, you know, why he's not
like just calling this SSRF and and I
guess it's because it is actually sort
of like the intended functionality of
>> the, you know, HTTP server at that
point, right?
connect. But I mean, if you scroll down
to the bottom, he's like, "Yeah, and
then you can just write a raw HTTP1,
>> you know, 1.1 request here and just
request example." Yeah. Example.com. Um,
and that'll be returned back to you. So,
uh, definitely another attack surface
here for HP2 um, to go after these.
>> Is that also basically a free proxy?
Like, could you just like use this as
tour nodes? Any any company that has
connect turned on? Just like
>> I'm sure it's rare, bro. I'm sure it's
rare.
>> Okay. It's got to be rare,
>> but it is it is good to see nonetheless.
Um, so I'll definitely add that to the
mass scanning for sure.
>> Um, all right. Any any final call outs
on that one or should I jump to
>> No, let's move on.
>> All right. Next up is the OG research of
course that we've covered on the pod
before. Next, JS uh pwnage by zero. Um,
like like I said, we've covered this,
but I do want to go back and kind of
break it down again because there are
some things that I I realized after
looking through it uh as a part of the
top 10 list that I think are really
valuable. Okay, so of course um this
research was, you know, caused a big a
big problem in the next.js community and
essentially was a cache poisoning
vulnerability um that allowed you to
just doss any page and uh later on get
stored XSS um under a certain set of
conditions. Um, and this vulnerability
breaks down to two component parts. One,
getting the route perceived as a data
request, which I'll I'll talk about in a
second. And two, making sure that the
correct uh cache control response header
was getting passed through. And since he
was able to do that, he was actually
able to affect the um internal caching
mechanism of Nex.js JS as compos or as
uh compared to you know how we're
normally doing cache poisoning which is
the difference between a CDN and a
backend server um and break any Nex.js
implementation that was just sitting out
there in the raw um which was pretty
sick. So um first I just wanted to
double click into that um internal cache
poisoning piece which is like not
something that we've seen a ton of and
these frameworks like next.js just have
their own internal caching mechanism
sometime and that is what zero is going
after here. Um so when you're doing
source code review of frameworks uh this
is a really good thing to look at uh
because it can often result in um this
sort of uh internal cache poisoning
scenario
>> and I feel like everything everything
now with AI writing code and stuff and
then also just companies wanting to
converge onto the biggest frameworks
things like Nex.js are super impactful
because there's so many sites running on
them.
>> Totally. Yeah. And and so I mean
targeting these frameworks as a whole I
think is just a really good idea and it
worked out really well for him. I think
he said in here let's see if I can find
it. Yeah. Uh this led to numerous
reports being submitted cumulatively
amounting to a beautiful six figure sub
in bounties. So he definitely like
cleaned up with this. Um and so yeah
that's the first piece is like make sure
you're looking for that internal caching
mechanism piece. And then the other
thing here which uh zero does a really
good job of is looking for um these
internal uh query parameters and
headers. So nextjs here is looking for
this um uh underscore
next data request or wreck uh query
parameter and that is being used to
determine whether this is a data request
or not. Right? And what what a data
request is is a request that should be
responding, you know, with with just the
data associated with this endpoint, not
the like HTML, you know, that goes back
to the user to be displayed on the page.
Yeah.
>> Um, and for me, that's kind of
reminiscent of like the Ruby on Rails,
you know,JSON thing, right? Where you're
able to like hit an endpoint, it'll
return HTML,
>> but then, you know, if you hit JSON at
the end, then it'll just dump a bunch of
JSON data back to you for that endpoint,
right?
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. and and so like I feel like
there's definitely other situations
where this sort of data request concept
is um is present. Um so I I could see
that being applicable to other
frameworks. Um, and then the other uh
thing he identified here was this X now
route matches header. And what that
allowed him to do was gain control of
the cache control header um to get a
value where he could get this actual,
you know, um, data request cached. And
um so as I was reading through this I
was like yeah but like you know that
that next data request query parameter
is going to be a part of the the cache
key and that's going to you know hack it
up. And that's actually a really
essential part of this is that next.js
is not actually considering uh the query
parameters as a part of the cache key.
>> Got it.
>> Um which is I think fairly unique uh
because I think normally they are but
not in this scenario. Um, but what comes
along with that is that now you don't
have a cache buster, right? So, how the
heck do you not just like nuke the
homepage of these websites when you're
trying to, you know, detect for this,
right? Um, and that's where the uh
technique, another technique that I
really liked came in, which is um zero
because he didn't have a, you know,
cache buster that he could put in the
query parameter, he actually addressed
his problem using the accept encoding
header. Um, and so the accept encoding
header was a part of the cache key here.
And uh, if we send them I'm going to
read from the from the um, actual write
up here. To address this, we can check
if the accept encoding header uh, is a
part of the cache key. And if it is, we
can send the malicious request without
the accept encoding header, allowing us
to check if the site is vulnerable
without impacting it. Right? because the
browser will always add that header to
the request which is going to make sure
that the normal users don't get hit with
that same uh cash poisoned.
>> That's so genius. What do you think he
would have done if he didn't have that
opportunity?
>> I don't know, man. He would have had to
find like he would have just had to nuke
[__] left and right and things would
have been going down. It would have been
bad.
>> Seriously, it's just like oh man, how
convenient. There just happens to be a
header that allows you to test this
without it bringing down everything.
>> Yeah. No, I think that's a really great
technique. And um so at the end of the
day, you know, what he ended up doing
was, you know, being able to hit the
endpoint with the underscore next data
request equals 1 and the X now route
matches header and that would return a
cachable JSON representation of that
specific page, right? That has some of
the data passed into it. Um and so then
that JSON representation would be cached
and anybody going there you know to
access the HTML version of the page
would just see the you know JSON version
which would cause you know catastrophic
>> breaks right
>> um and then later on he was actually
able to get stored XSS because it was
still actually rendering that JSON with
the text HTML content type since the
underscore
>> Yeah. Exactly. So it's like oh no
genius. And then anything any data
passed into that you know JSON blob
>> could be used to trigger. So he said a
lot of the times the user agent was
actually getting passed in you know into
that JSON. Um and then you know
triggering on the page a stored XSS
which is just like an absolute nightmare
situation for for Nex.js.
>> Absolutely insane dude.
>> Yeah. So right Zero puts out so much
stuff.
>> Yeah it's it's good man. Um it's really
good stuff. So definitely a good thing
to take a look at uh if you're ever
targeting Nex.js or if you're going to
go look at a framework in general, these
internal caching mechanisms, these um
you know internal uh headers and query
parameters that affect the internal
functioning of these frameworks really
really valuable scope I think.
>> Yeah. Genius. You want to jump to the
next one?
>> Yeah. Um you want me to take it or you
got it?
>> No, I'm not. I'm up next. I'm going to
jump to five.
>> Okay. All right.
>> All right, dude. So this is soap pone or
soap pone.
>> Oh jeez. I'm glad you knew the straw.
>> Yeah. I I sent this to Justin. We we got
we kind of split this up a little bit
with like server side client side. And
uh I claimed this one. And then when I
opened it and it was 93 pages, I sent
Justin the meme of uh from Brooklyn 999
of him going cool cool.
>> Uh
>> it happens every year, man. I I think
Joel last year got like a 120 page like
paper as well that he had to go into on
net stuff. So it's it's always the net
stuff that's just so long and
complicated.
>> Yes. Um I'm not going to share my
screen. It's 93 pages. I don't need to
scroll through it, but I will I did
actually use AI to like process it and
understand it really well. And so I
think that um yeah, so I'll give you a
good overview. And if you're obsessed
with net or you think this is
interesting then you should go dive into
it. But basically, actually, let me get
a little bit of author attribution here.
So, this is from Watchtower by Pota
Bazidlo.
>> Yeah, this guy's a beast. This guy's a
freaking beast.
>> Yeah, he's the principal vulnerab
vulnerability researcher at Watchtower.
So, uh, the full title is Poning.NET
Framework Applications through HTTP
client proxies and WSDL, which by the
way, I loved finding WSDL files back in
the day all over Yahoo. I don't really
find them much anymore, which is kind of
frustrating. But did you ever run into
those?
>> Oh, yeah. Dude, those those things were
great. And they really just give a bunch
of insight. So, I'm excited to see how
he's going to handle these here because
I've read I've read a bunch of his
stuff, but I have not sorted through
this 93page paper. So,
>> yeah. So, it's a quirk in hownet handles
HTTP client proxies and then the WSDL.
So, the and just up front, I know
sometimes I think things are way more
interesting when you state the the
impact first. So the downstream impact
of this was arbitrary file write then
NLM like credential theft and then
actually rce and so um and there's some
drama around it but I'll get to that in
a second. So the cool the core
vulnerability is basically there's some
code that is casting input into um and
the classes that it's in it's HTTP web
client protocol but this class is used
to cast like SOAP messages into HTTP web
requests and whenever it's initializing
it or whatever it's it's it's always
attempting it to cast it with uh the as
operator
>> and what that means is if instead of
using like an HTTP uh URI, you use a
file or NLM or whatever URI, it gets
cast to a different object type.
>> Dude, I did see this. I did see this.
>> And here's the really weird part is that
when it fails, if it doesn't cast it, it
returns null,
>> but then it and then there's no checks.
Oh, at the end it does check if it's
null, but if it is null, it just skips
the HTTP specific setup stuff, but
continues in the rest of the flow
without throwing any other errors. So,
so your ob your object which you got
past all of the HTTP processing is now
just going to be processed normally by
the rest of the code and it only skipped
the part that would have broken and
saved the day had it actually occurred.
Right.
>> That's amazing.
>> Yeah. So, it gets c like so with the
file operator it gets cast into a file
web request instead of an HTTP web
request. So, then it skips the HTTP
processing but then the rest of the code
still basically just writes it straight
to disk. So, so you're able to write the
XML straight to disk. And when you do
that, um, apparently you were able to I
didn't actually get that deep into the
document, but apparently he's able to
store that as a CS, HTML or an aspx
file. And so then it's just an instant
web shell.
>> And then in the
>> Yeah, which is amazing, right? And then
in the cases where that where that
doesn't work, you can supply UNC path
and when the server tries to write to
that UNC share instead, you get the NLM
uh hash like O hash from that request
and then you can go crack it offline and
then now you've cracked the NLM hash. So
yeah. Um yeah, insane.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. This is Yeah, this is
lit. I I I So I realized what happened
with this. there was a you know I don't
know friendly version of this research
that was uh in a you know in a web write
up not like a 93 you know page research
paper and that was what I read and I
just and I think we actually even
covered it on the podcast where you know
it's just like oh just like yeet this
whole HTTP request into a file you know
y
>> um so dude I freaking love stuff like
this man it is uh it is hilarious to see
that this actually worked and that it
skipped that one block of code that it
needed
>> to actually if it tried to parse it and
it was a file instead of a web request,
it would have just broken at that point.
>> So anyways,
>> wow. All right, dude. Um, okay. So
number six, definitely definitely gonna
uh take a look at that again and
understand a little bit more about um
when this is actually applicable. Uh it
it says it said up here it's basically a
quirk in hownet handles HTP client
proxies. So whenever we're dealing with
client proxies and stuff like that,
that's when we should look into this and
maybe get our cherry file right.
>> Yes. in RC. That's crazy, man. Um, okay.
Where am I jumping? Am I jumping back up
to six?
>> Yes.
>> All right, jumping up to six. Uh, we
actually also covered this on the pod.
Um, but this is the, um, research by,
uh, Kaneko Takkeshi, uh, which is
cross-sight E tag length leaks.
>> Um, and I actually feel like last time
on the pod, we did a pretty good job of
explaining how this works. Y
>> um so I'm not going to like go super
indepth on this but I did want to
highlight a couple things that I just
want to make sure you guys understand
about this because uh I think there are
some misconceptions about how yeah well
I I think a lot of these things that are
originating in CTFs have some pretty
difficult preconditions that are of
course are contrived for the CTF purpose
right but are not always present in um
>> in the actual you know exploitation
scenarios. So, um the first piece here
was that uh if you read this cross-sight
e tag length leak and had a diff
difficult time understanding it, uh one
of the the the preconditions for this
attack to actually work was that you
have to have a curf that can allow you
to control the length of the response
where you are doing this uh you know
cross-sight
>> um request here. So, you know what they
do here is they use um let's see if I
can find it here. uh they use a sea surf
to create notes, right? Um which you can
see right here for those of you watching
on YouTube. Uh where they, you know,
butt the um you know the response size
of their guess right up to the um E tag
juncture point. And um the reason that's
important is because the way that this
cross-sight leak is triggered is by
creating a one bite differential in the
E tag header,
>> right?
um which is uh returned in the response
of the request and then gets included by
the browser in the uh next request that
gets sent to that same endpoint.
>> And that one bite difference you butt
right up to the NodeJS uh 431 maximum
request size
>> um uh you know buffer, right? Where it
says, "Okay, we only can have 16
kilobytes as the request size and if you
go over that, we're just going to return
a 431, right?"
>> Mhm. Um so it's very important that you
have a seurf to be able to get the
response size right up to um a certain
juncture point where just your notes
>> and the actual secret if searched via a
cross-sight search will push it over
that um juncture point with the hex
representation of the content length
>> uh and create a uh you know one bite
difference in the e tag header which
will then result in the 431. Um, so it's
kind of a monster to explain from a
verbal perspective, but what I want the
user to understand here or the listener
to understand here is that the curf is a
really important part of this exploit.
So, um, just keep that in mind. And
really what I what I think is more
applicable for bug bounty is the Chrome
um history API piece here where the 431
if you're able to trigger it right which
is a an error status code um request
header fields are too large um Chrome is
not embedding that um is not considering
that as a navigation in the Chrome
history API. It is actually replacing
the current navigation. So if you are
able to trigger this, you will not see a
change in the history length. Uh it will
it will just be the same. Um and I think
that is a very applicable piece that can
be used in other cross-sight um leaks uh
in other in other areas um in other
applications that's a little bit more
applicable um than the whole E tag piece
here. Uh so I know that that's a little
bit complicated. Did you did Joseph did
you get any of that or am I just like am
I talking to the wind here?
>> No, it's perfect. I think that like you
said the initial explanation that we did
on the other episode was really really
good and then on top of that I think
that the clarification the most
important thing you're saying is that
basically
>> in this case there was like kind is it
was a bit contrived. It's not that
realistic that you'd have CSRF where you
can control the content length in that
type of granularity. Um, yeah,
>> but I do think I do think that really
blogs like this when you read them,
>> what it helps you hone is your ability
to spot
>> um things that should not be possible,
right? Like I think that
>> anomalies here. Yeah, anomalies like
like you know the fact that the E tag
can like move by one character and that
that's influencable cross- sight is very
interesting and I think that things like
that will lead to bugs when people are
thinking about you know specifically
like the little gadgets they have for
anything that happens cross- sight.
That's a great point because it's
actually that and that goes to another
point that I had on this too which is
you know it the E tag header that is
returned in the response right is
actually getting reflected into the if
none match header when you reerequest
the same URL right and so actually
what's happening here is something
that's extremely unique which is you
know a response header is being
reflected back into a request header and
that request header is being used to ex
to you know overflow the request header
maximum size right
>> um which is I think very interesting and
that you don't have access to that if
none match header value you know if you
did even though it's a part of the
request you know you don't have access
to that uh you have no control over it
that's something that's controlled by
the browser so I think that principle is
a lot more you know cross-applicable to
other exploitation scenarios probably
than exactly this e tag scenario
>> right
>> yeah so anyway not not not to [__] on
the research at all it like
mindblowingly beautiful. As a clientside
hacker, when I read this, I I weep tears
of joy. Yeah. You know, because I'm
like, "Wow, what a masterpiece. What a
breakdown of primitives, right?" Like,
you know, and the one bite differential
allows you to, you know, exploit this.
Uh so, yeah, I I think that it still
makes me very happy to read for sure.
>> Oh, yeah. It's insane. That's even
possible.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> All right, we got 20 minutes. We got to
we got to crank these out. Um, I have
two left and you have two left. Perfect.
>> All right. Number four is Loft and
Translation: Exploiting Unicode
Normalization by our boy Ryan. And he
also presented this to the critical
thinkers um on top of doing it at Black
Hat USA.
>> Freaking love that.
>> And so, yeah, I would say go check out
the recording, but I don't even know if
we recorded it because it's on YouTube
under Black Hat USA. So, the link will
be in the bio. But what uh Ryan and it
was his daughter, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Isabella as well and we did
we did record the critical thinkers talk
as well so that
>> I don't know if it was different or what
>> no it'll be in the exclusive content in
discord and it was different so very
good content there
>> sweet yeah um so anyone who has not done
that I'll do a quick overview of
basically what he what they covered um
the first was that the agenda really is
talking all about unicord unic code
normalization but to break that break
that down further they talked about
decoding errors truncation confusables
casing and then combining diiocritics.
What are you laughing about over there,
>> dude? It's just such a, you know, crazy
piece of research. Like, yeah, like like
to hear you like just rattle off those
various sections to this research is
like insane. They did such a good job on
it, man.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I think the coolest part
about the decoding errors was that they
talked about over long encodings and uh
I loved his analogy of basically it's
like a box in a box in a box you get
from uh Amazon or whatever.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And so basically you
can overlong encode typical ASI. So you
can have an A that instead of being one
bite is two bytes or three bytes and
it's still just a normal A. It's not
like some weird Unicode character. It's
still just a typical A, but it's called
an overlong encoding. And so sometimes
that'll let it bypass spec specific
regular expressions that are checking
for malicious things on the like at the
beginning before it's then decoded or
normalized later. Um, and so that can be
really valuable. The second thing they
talked about was bite truncation which
is where um certain bytes which are long
like the uh three byte Chinese character
that can then be you know converted down
or truncated down into like a CRLF feed
um or like a carriage return or line
feed. So um this specifically had a lot
of impact in a bug bounty finding where
and by the way I'm not showing anything
on screen because it's a video but their
their slide deck's really good though.
Um and so you can uh and they suspect
they suspected that this was due to
differences between little Indian and
big Indian big Indian ordering and um
they show a really good example that
uses cyershe
>> um to to actually you know show how this
would would happen. Then the
>> I love that diagram man that that was
such a good representation of it. I
never have I looked so closely at
Unicode and felt like I understood what
I was looking at because Unicode is
hecked bro. So hot take. I think that's
why this did so well both in the top 10
and just for people, they finally made
it super understandable. Like even just
the way that I just described overong
and coding,
>> I like you could have talked to me about
that 10 different times over the last
two years and I wouldn't have remembered
it. But but the way he described it with
the boxes, it's just like, okay, now I
understand this, right?
>> Same for what you're talking about.
>> Um,
>> so then there's one called confusables,
which are I think this is probably what
most people think of when they think of
Unicode normalization. It's like these
characters get confused due to like best
fit mappings or worst fit. And this is
like kind of hearkening back to all of
the Orange Sai research for worst fit.
Um, and they share a few more examples
of that which I thought was good. Then
casing. I had never heard of this one
until the talk which I thought was
really neat. And it's it's it's so good
that they use something so like web app
specific. They used a script tag where
the I was a Latin small letter dotless
I.
And then basically if the backend
application did something like um
decoded it and then called likeupper
that that weird dotless eye becomes an
eye. Even though it wasn't normally an
eye, it now gets converted into an eye.
And so if there's any kind of detection
logic or any kind of W that's before
that, it would have never been caught.
But when that happens on the second
half, it actually does get caught and
works quite well. Um and then they did
combining diioritics which uh to be
clear is the one I understood the least
but is also really cool. So like there
is some unic code that's basically
combining characters. For example like
greater than and then a slash becomes
like not greater than and then the not
greater than symbol sometimes gets like
uh converted to greater than which
obviously when you're looking for like
HTML tags or script tags that's like
when that's really valuable. So
yeah, I think that's all the things. Um
the
>> that I I just wanted to add because I I
had to pull it up while you were talking
about that. Like the casing thing was
actually my first introduction into um
you know Unicode.
>> Oh, really?
>> Problems. Yeah, actually it was from a
live hacking event back in like
>> man, it's almost 10 years ago now. And I
was talking to Bit K, the researcher at
Yes We Hack. Actually, let me flex my
Yes, we hack hood hoodie right here. and
um and he gave me this website, you
know, that he built that showed some of
the Unicode transformations on on
JavaScript whenever you run two
uppercase or dot uh two lowercase. And
uh you know, his handle is bit K. And
one of the the most impactful
transformations is actually one of these
weird unic code K's that I I I couldn't
find the unic code value for in this
moment. But and if you do two lowercase
on that, it turns to a lowercase K,
right? A lot of the other ones are like
two uppercase, right? Which is a lot
more rare,
>> but uh there's a ton of situations where
you do lowercase.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so this special K will get
converted into a a lowercase K. uh if
you run lowercase on it. That's sick. Um
yeah, so it's pretty it's pretty cool
stuff and I've I've I always thought it
was awesome, dude, that it aligns with
his name bit K, you know, because he can
use the special K in his as the last
character and when it gets turned into a
K.
>> Yeah, I need to come up with a handle
that that has some like acrylics or
something in it.
>> The um yeah, they they used a K in their
talk, too, and it was the Kelvin K. So,
it might be the same one.
>> Oh, it might be the It actually looks
like the Kelvin K. I got to grab the
Unicode code point for this thing. Hold
on. Yeah. Yeah. They talked specifically
about Kelvin K and how there was like
some check in active scanner or
something in in verb or something that
like checks for that.
>> Dude, I don't know how to get the unic
code point for this quick quick enough
here.
>> No, you're fine.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, no. Yeah. So, it's unic code point
212A.
Uh, so whatever that is.
>> Nice.
>> All right. What's up next?
>> You're up on OM leaking more than you
joined for. This is second place. This
was such this was such cool research,
man. Um, okay. I'm excited to talk about
this. So, we've covered some of this
research before on the podcast. I don't
know whether we uh covered this exact
one, but after reading this, I am
thoroughly convinced that OM links are
the new SQLI, bro. Because if you're
looking through each one of these um,
you know, frameworks that they're just
like slaughtering in this write up, uh,
it's pretty it's pretty gnarly. And um
so the TLDDR of the situation is you get
a lot of um frameworks that allow you to
do you know filters and searches and
queries and stuff like that.
>> And um depending on the way that that is
implemented and mapped to SQL on the
back end uh there are a lot of crazy
things you can do. For example,
filtering if you're searching through
users filtering on like their password
field and stuff like that. Um yeah, and
it affects a ton of different um uh OM
um you know frameworks for for all this
stuff.
>> My brain is like a slot machine like
rolling and just thinking or maybe a
rolodex of all the times I've had like
um for example like user enumer like
user searches where like you put in like
one or two characters and it shows a few
of them.
>> Is that the is that the times when this
would be would this be applicable?
>> Yes. Yes. And and also you know you can
you can um also do some situations where
uh like if you have a field and an
operation that you're able to like
search on then you can do for example
like password starts with or whatever.
Um, so anyway, the the write up goes
through a bunch of different ways to
bypass, you know, filters and blacklists
for um these types of uh OM filters. Uh,
and there's a lot of really good
takeaways in there. There's actually a
section in a lot of the areas called key
takeaways. Yeah, you can see right here,
I'm showing it on the screen. Yeah.
>> Where it talks about what things they
learned about these OM leaks from each
framework uh that they audited. Um, and
a couple of them are uh that I I'll I'll
just mention right here are look for
areas where you can provide a field and
an operator because that really like
enhances your ability to to search. Um,
definitely look for these sort of
underscore underscore situations, right?
Like I've seen these inquiry parameters
all the time. Where where is it? Right
here.
>> Me too. Yeah.
>> Um,
>> there it is right here. You know, like
email email starts with or something
like that, right? If you're seeing
something like that, then that's
definitely something you want to double
click into. Um, additionally, they say
even if the operator like starts with
and stuff like that are not available,
don't sleep on the logical operators as
well like greater than or less than
because you can still do sort of binary
searches, right? Uh, on that, you know,
using that operation.
>> Yeah, it's huge.
>> Yeah. And, uh, they they do add a whole
list at the end. Let me see if I can
find it. Um but you do run into some
difficulties with that uh based on
database collation. Um so some of the
databases will not sort characters the
way that you think they will sort
characters. So um you may have some
difficulty performing those searches uh
based off of uh the way that the
database collation works. Um but they do
some really in-depth research on each of
the databases here. MSQL, Mariab, MySQL.
um Postgress, all of these sort of
explaining how to um understand how the
databases compare strings uh if you're
trying to do like a greater than or less
than comparison. Um so really good stuff
there. Some databases are also um like
not case sensitive, which causes a
problem as well. Uh but they have
solutions for a lot of this stuff inside
the article.
>> Dude, I cannot wait to add this as a
skill to my cloud code. I'm like dying
for it right now. I'm not joking. Well,
dude. Okay, that's what I was saying
before. Um, was when I looked at this, I
was like, "Oh, man." You know, I feel
like I've seen something similar to
this. Yes.
>> In this target I was hacking on. So, I I
kicked off Cloud Code to go hack it
while I was finishing up research. And
it found I just gave it the article. I
was like, "Hey, like apply some of these
techniques
>> to this host." And then it came back
with a bunch of PII, dude. You know,
it's crazy when your when your your
cloud code is like, "And here's PII."
I'm like, "Oh my gosh, I love it."
>> Mine's usually the opposite. It's like
critical CSRF cores issue. And I'm like,
"No, it's not. Shut up."
>> No, no, no, stop. Um, the the other big
takeaway I had from this one is that a
lot of times, you know, there will be
some filtering on like what um
operations you can use like not or
starts with or whatever. And one of the
um tricks they gave to bypass that is if
you use the um sort of query parameter
format of key and then square bracket
another value square bracket equals
>> you know value right then sometimes that
will map to the JSON representation that
is needed for some of these OM um
operations. So the the example they gave
is reset token square bracket not close
square bracket equals e.
>> Right. So that would map to reset in
JSON reset token colon new object not
colon e.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And uh and so when that that maps
out a lot of times that will allow you
to pass uh bypass middleware parsers for
um sort of malicious queries going into
the OM.
>> Nice. Yeah. I love uh the way that when
you convert embedded or like deep JSON
back to uh URL encoded forms or what or
not or post body forms. Yeah.
>> X WW form URL encoding.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I'll never forget that string and I'll
never forget it.
>> Yeah. It's super useful
>> uh to do those conversions. I I still
find GraphQL where
>> uh it's like you where you don't have
CSRF because it's JSON, but then you
convert it and it works fine and you
have CSRF via GraphQL. Yeah, that's a
good one.
>> Yeah. Uh for the listener in case that
wasn't super obvious basically uh what
we were just talking about or not what
we were just talking about the comment I
just made was for anytime you have
GraphQL that's cookie protected and it's
happening via JSON request if you
convert it to a URL encoded form it will
if it still works then you have CSRF and
you can just go ahead and report that.
So
>> assuming there's a mutation. Yeah,
exactly. You have to have mutation
because otherwise it's just a get
request which you don't you can't uh see
the response of.
>> All right, we have like 5 to 10 minutes
left and we've got two techniques to do.
>> Luckily uh number three which I'm doing
from uh search ser search light cyber
team uh Chev's company that was acquired
um
>> is and actually did you see like their
CTO or something his partner
>> Michael became the CEO dude
>> right? But it was but he was the CTO for
asset note right and then he became
>> was CTO Michael was um CEO of asset note
and then he got he became CEO of search
light cyber which is pretty sick. So,
who's acquiring who? I'm the captain
now, right? Come on. Um, yeah. So, we
covered this actually really well back
then and it's a very short write up, so
it will it'll take just a second here,
but uh just as a recap, they were they
had a blind SSRF that they wanted to
escalate. And as everyone knows, blind
SSRF kind of sucks. So, they were trying
to make it full read and the first thing
they do is play with redirects and it
was kind of it was not it was not
useful. Basically, they just kept
getting exception colon invalid JSON and
they but they increased the number of
redirects and for some reason they could
like get it to follow up to 30 and then
it got a different exception and it said
like network exception instead of
invalid JSON. So that kind of got them
like thinking like oh what should we do
here or whatever and um they moved on to
testing other status codes because they
thought they might be treated
differently and sure enough on a 500 it
gave them the full response. So that
kind of just like got them thinking like
maybe there's some way to get a full
response if we do other response codes.
So they wrote a little script that would
and this is so still so confusing that
it worked. I don't know if you remember
how confusing this is.
>> Basically they had to do multiple
redirects and on each redirect it
increased the status code. So the first
response was 301 then 302 then 303 and
um and then at the very end they would
have it go to the AWS um metadata IM
endpoint. And when they did that, when
they hit the cloud metadata endpoint
after a bunch of those redirects, it
actually worked. And um and they still
were like really confused just like you
and I about why that works. And I'm just
going to read this paragraph because I
still don't it still doesn't really it
still it's not a satisfying answer, but
at least made sense. It says, "But why
did it work? This drove us nuts."
>> But hold up. You know, like I also just
have to appreciate like whoever is
writing this here. I don't know if it's
Shubs or the other people from the the
Aseno team, but he says this drove us
nuts. this was, you know, like he's
saying a bunch of things in here and
it's like it makes me feel a little bit
better that he's also like what the
freak is going on, you know?
>> Yeah.
>> This drove us nuts. Was there something
special about the 305 status code? Even
though we performed a redirect from 301
to 310, why did we only get the
responses starting at 305? So, they ran
that script. It started at 301, it
escalated up to 310 and then they had it
uh do the the redirect to the cloud
metadata. But for some reason in the
final response they got it included all
of the responses like all of the um all
of the redirect uh server side response
is that include like you know the the
response headers like content type,
content length, connection, server,
location.
>> Um but it only started at 305. It didn't
show 301 to 304, which is super
confusing. So anyways, that's why he's
saying, was there something special
about 305? Even though we performed a
redirect from 301 to 310, why did we
only get the responses from 305 and
beyond? Was it an issue with lib curl?
After extensive analysis, we're
convinced no, we don't think so.
Instead, we think that the application
was happy to follow a few redirects and
was failing on that JSON parsing we saw
initially and was not happy about
following more than max redirects
configured for lib curl. However, there
was an error state when it followed more
than five, not handled by lib curl, but
rather by the application itself. Says
this technique may sound obscure to you,
and I agree, but it's now worked for us
in several different situations where we
would not have been able to see the full
response code. I just I'm It's so weird.
It has to be like a configuration of a
text stack that's not uncommon. That's
like pretty common, right? Like lots of
companies are using because otherwise,
how would they have found it multiple
times? But anyways, this drives me nuts.
But it's so freaking cool to go from a
blind SRF to a full RES SRF with this
technique.
>> Oh my gosh, dude. Like can you just
imagine like I'm getting a little high
from just thinking about it. Like it's
like oh my gosh, this uh how much of a
high it would be to go from a blind SSRF
that and you know I'm thinking about it
in the context of the live hacking
events too where everybody's like oh
yeah I got that blind SSRF and you go
you know you go there and you're like
hey did you get anything with it? No.
Did you get anything with it? And then
freaking Shubs comes in. He's like yeah
I got full read. We're like,
>> "All right,
>> how how did you do it?"
>> Oh, I don't know
>> the script. Anyways, all right, dude. We
got like five minutes. Do do number one.
And by the way, everyone, this is the
number one voted Porswiger top 10. So,
>> yeah. Um, really loved that past
research. So fun to review that. And,
uh, yeah, I'll jump to to number one
now. Um, this one was really cool and
this was just really wellperformed
research in my opinion. Um this is by
Vladco 312.
Um and essentially is providing new
techniques for exploiting um SSTI. Okay.
And uh these two techniques are called
uh error based exploitation and boolean
error based blind SSTI. And um he
borrows a lot of the concepts for this
from
>> Hey, sorry to cut up. He he just pushed
improvements yesterday to this. Oh, look
at that. He did.
>> I'm sharing my screen so we can see. Oh,
wow. Dude, he's adding Oh my gosh. He's
adding new uh freaking
>> dude template. Oh my gosh, what a
baller. He's adding new templates to it
right away. Uh I guess probably
something to do with um you know,
getting in the top 10. Um that's
amazing. So yeah, this research, dude,
let me tell you, this was some of the
most thoroughly done research I've seen
in a long time. Okay, not only is he
bringing two new ways to exploit SSTI,
but he's also cross referencing this
across a bunch of different templating
engines, a bunch of different
programming languages. So
>> and and providing generic payloads that
work across multiple programming
languages
>> uh that you can use for
>> that's amazing, dude.
>> So it's freaking sick. and he's
integrating all of this into SSTI map, a
tool, um to exploit these kind of
vulnerabilities. So, um let me kind of
go through some of these techniques. Um
a lot of you guys that are familiar with
some of the OG, you know, uh SQLI
exploitation methods will kind of this
will make a lot of sense to you. Um but
essentially the first one is error-based
exploitation and it's essentially
getting um and this is also used often
in XXE but getting um an error to
trigger in the templating engine and
having that error displayed on the on
the screen to the user.
>> So uh he was experimenting he kind of
goes through a pretty long intro there
where he talks about how he discovered
this stuff. Um but the way he ends up um
you know exploiting this is uh
triggering an error um using get adder
in Python uh which is for getting
attributes and then concating whatever
he wants the output of and that will
will trigger um an error uh that says
you know string has no attribute
whatever right whatever output you
passed in and that output then in this
scenario um you know the contents of
Etsy password will then be leaked in
that error.
uh in that actual error message. Um and
if verbose errors are on in the
application then that full uh output
will be displayed to the user. Um which
is really really helpful. Um and he
mentioned that he tried to do integer
conversion with this as well. Um but
integer conversion truncates the data at
I think what is it like 199 characters.
Yeah. Um but he found in Python that you
can use get adder which does not have a
limit on the amount of data that you can
pass into it and leak out. Um so he does
this. I think Python is a really good
example of how to do this. Um and he
provides a sort of polyglot that works
uh across all tested Python-based
template engines. Um which is amazing.
uh but he also provides polyglot
payloads
um for detecting these these error based
oracles and for that he does uh a
division by zero um payload uh and the
way that he does that is uh I guess
quotation mark no parenthesis
>> parenthesis one divided by 0xy.zxy
cxy and this will result in an error in
any programming language that he tested
here. Um and if that error comes back
then you can use that as a way to
determine okay wow um
>> error based oracles for SSTI in this
scenario is kind of the way to go and
then you you pick from the variety of uh
you know error based payloads he gives
you in Python, PHP, Java, Ruby,
Noode.js, JS, Elixir, all of these.
>> Um, so
>> can we respect the fact that he's doing
a lot of this testing via some sort of
like Discord bot?
>> He knows that there's a bunch of the
screen there's a bunch of the
screenshots where
>> like go to the go to like the fourth
screenshot he's doing like slash test
and then putting in some content and
then it's doing some sort of test under
the hood and then it's showing him the
response. He's like testing stuff from
Discord. I love it.
>> What a badass man. Yeah, dude.
This is exactly how you use cloud code
too. You you just like uh just talk to
it all the time in Discord
>> which is great.
>> Um so that was the error based
exploitation. We see similar stuff in
XXE error based um you know leaks for
XXE. Um and then the second type he
mentioned was boolean error-based blind
SSTI.
Okay. And this is a similar situation
where um you've got an error based SSTI
but it's resulting only in a 500 from
the server. Right?
>> Um so what he does here is use a similar
concept with you know one divided by
some expression and that expression
should be cast or evaluate to zero and
if it does then it triggers a divide by
zero exception and will cause a 500 from
the server. And so using that you have a
boolean yes or no. Did my expression
resolve to zero. Uh and that can allow
you to leak valuable data in the
application when you have the full set
of SSTI um expressions at your disposal.
>> Um
>> so he also provides some generic
detection payloads for this. Uh these
ones actually take advantage of uh
syntax errors for generic detection. Um,
those are located at the bottom of the
article. Um, I I won't read them out
because it's just going to be hard to
like explain to you that there's syntax
errors here, but for any of those of you
watching on YouTube, you guys can
clearly see the syntax errors in the
location of the paren or of the um yeah,
parenthesis in this uh in this
expression which will trigger the the
error message um whenever you're using
your scanner. So very thoroughly done
research um built it into a tool,
documented all of the nuances in
different programming languages.
>> It's no wonder this was number one. No
wonder it's so good in every way. Makes
me want to go test for it everywhere.
It's like insane.
>> Dude, I I very rarely find SSTI. I think
that is one area where I really need to
improve as a hacker is looking for SSTI
because it's so valuable, too. Um all
right, shout out to Vladco for that. Um,
I did want to say I know you got to go
Joseph, so feel free to drop if you need
to, but I did have one little quick
story. I actually combined the OM
research with this blind boolean error
based attack one time, and I kind of
wanted to to tell them about it. So, I'm
>> I'm going to do a quick little stories
here. So, um, I was testing an
application where I had a secondary
context path traversal. And I've talked
about this on the pod before, the
specific instance. I won't tell you
which one, but um we had a secondary
context path traversal and I was
actually able to inject Microsoft graph
uh O data um filters
>> um in there and this allowed me to do
stuff like okay if username equals
rhinorator then you know return that in
the response right uh apply filters
there so they patched that whole thing
and made it so that I couldn't get the
data back out but I knew that I was
still getting this O data injection
right in the back Yeah.
>> So what I ended up doing was crafting an
O data query um where
>> you know it was like starts with a
specific ID and and username is equal to
whatever user I wanted to target. Uh
first name is equal to this or divide by
zero.
>> No,
>> right divide, you know, ID by zero. So
if you know if the first name started
with whatever right then it would not
hit that second divide by zero condition
that divide the ID by zero
>> but if it didn't then I I would hit it
and it would trigger an error right so
and I was able to detect that error out
through the secondary context path
traversal because it was reflecting
error conditions back up
>> even though it blocked the JSON
response. Um so using that we were able
to also arbitrarily leak data about
users. The fact that the fact that you
and him both converged on a divide by
zero payload
>> like just goes to show that you're all
genius. I think personally I just think
that's like really neat that both of
y'all's heads like that two people who
are really intelligent who are looking
at this like similar problem came to the
same conclusion is like very cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I like it too. It's very
valuable for triggering error based uh
oracles in my opinion. So all right man
GG. I think that's a wrap on Portswicker
top 10. Yeah.
>> Perfect. Yep. Peace.
>> All right. Peace y'all.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.